# Archana V Banking Professional

# **My Contact**

aarch86@gmail.com

**©** 8792811404

No.13/2, Muninarasimiah Garden, BTM I Stage, Bengaluru 560029

## **Hard Skills**

- Financial and Credit Analysis
- Balance sheet and Ratio Analysis
- MSME and Retail Loans- Appraisal, Processing and Documentation
- Front End Banking Operations
- Cash, Deposits and CASA Management
- Strong knowledge of Banking regulations and Compliance

## **Soft Skills**

- Relationship building and customer
  service
- Team Leadership and Management
- Excellent communication and Interpersonal Skills
- Attention to detail and strong analytical abilities

# **Education**

Indian Institute of Banking and Finance
 CAIIB

Completed in 2014

 Bharathiar School of Management and Entrepreneur Development, Bharathiar University, Coimbatore

Master of Business Administration, specialization in Finance and HR

Completed in 2008

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore

Bachelor of Science in Apparel and Fashion Technology

Completed in 2006

### **About Me**

Highly skilled and dedicated banking professional with 10 years of experience in Canara Bank, excelling in various areas such as credit analysis, loans processing and documentation, financial analysis and front end operations including Cash, CASA and Deposits.
Currently working as a Manager in Canara bank, Attibele Branch, seeking to leverage extensive knowledge and expertise to contribute to an organization's growth and success

# **Professional Experience**

#### Manager in Canara Bank, Attibele Branch, Bengaluru April 2023- present

- Lead and oversee a team of banking professionals, ensuring efficient daily operations and adherence to regulatory standards.
- Execute credit and financial analysis, assessing and evaluating loan applications, loans processing and documentation and ensuring compliance with legal and regulatory standards
- Play a key role in front-end operations including cash management, customer account and service activities and Deposits.
- Provide guidance to and support to branch staff resolving complex customer inquiries and issues effectively.
- Drive business development efforts, identifying and capitalizing on cross selling opportunities to promote banking products and services.
- Develop and nurture strong relationships with existing and prospective clients, ensuring high levels of customer satisfaction and retention.

#### Officer in Canara Bank, Ashoka Pillar Branch, Bengaluru April 2020 - March 2023

- Conducted credit analysis and loan appraisals, reviewed customer financial statements and prepared credit reports.
- Processed MSME and Retail loan applications, executed documentation and ensured timely disbursal of funds.
- Played a key role in takeover of MSME credit limits and Monitored and managed a portfolio of clients, ensuring timely loan repayment and resolving any issues or concerns.
- Handled front end operations including CASA and Deposit counters

#### Single Window Operator in Canara bank Chandapur Circle Branch and Hosur Main Branch June 2013 -March 2020

- Handled front end operations and worked in various counters including CASH, CASA and Deposits.
- Processed loan applications and executed loan documents

Languages English, Tamil, Kannada and Telugu

References Available upon request